James Gross NLRB Files /4057
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series III. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD 7/35-11/47
  - Sub-Series A. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD RECORDS
    - Sub-Series 2. CORRESPONDENCE 7/19/35-3/19/70
      - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 29)
        Undated; Correspondence concerning George O. Pratt's discussion of constitutionality; Rosenberg on the Walsh Amendment (8pp); suggested amendment to provide for mediation in the maritime industry, interstate trucking and bus business; interpretation and application of amendment to the Appropriations Act; conduct under congressional subpoena; where litigation viewpoint errors; position structure; supplementary instructions to trial examiners; Sec.9(c) cases.
    - Sub-Series 3. REPORTS AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS 7/35-1972
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 30)
        7/35-9/35; concerning the bargaining unit; selection of test cases; rule VIII of the National Labor Relations Board Act; report to the President (7/34-9/35) (35pp+); drafts of instructions to staff members; removal of cases; conference with Nylander and Hope; Rules and Regulations ser.1; Millis' address; venue of injunction suits; Congressional findings in the NLRA.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 31)
        10/35-12/35; pertaining to Madden's address on the NLRA; monthly reports by region.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        relating to administrative questions and suggestions from regional offices; economic data; monthly report by region; Madden's address on the Guffey Coal Decision; conference between the executive board and the union; status of litigation; Edwin S. Smith's address; tables.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 33)
        1/37-4/37; include an excerpt from Blankenhorn's personal files regarding the General Motors strike; monthly report by region; confidential regional officers' comments on the current labor situation.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 34)
        5/37-8/37; include confidential regional officers' comments on the current labor situation; excerpt from Madden's speech on collective bargaining.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        9/37-12/37; concerning Madden's and Fahy's addresses on the NLRA; Herrick's "The Record Speaks"; the regional conference; Governor Charles H. Martin's (Oregon) speech.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        1/38-6/38; pertaining to the trial examiners' union; Committee on Labor, Education and Social Security report; addresses of Madden
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        7/38-12/38; include comments on the current labor situation (with a reference to "Bloody Harlan"); excerpt from The Manchester Guardian Weekly (England); partial records of the regional conference; Beatrice Stern's address; NLRB decision in disputes between unions affiliated with National Federations; addresses of Madden.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        1/39-2/39; relating to the Walsh Amendments; benefits secured for A.F. ofL., C.I.O. and unaffilated unions; S.1392 (Holman Bill); separation of enforcement and judicatory functions.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        4/39-5/39; concerning the NLRB Union; confidential regional officers' comments on current labor situation; instructions to trial examiners (30pp+); remarks of Madden at the Atlanta Institute of Labor Law.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 6)
        5/39-6/39; regarding the Special Conference Committee of the Economic Division (80pp); economic reasons for NLRB jurisdiction over agricultural workers (68pp); Aaron W. Warner speech.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        7/39-8/39; pertaining to Rules and Regulations, ser. 2; H.R. 258; report of investigation of the Los Angeles office (100pp+).
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        9/39-10/39; concerning Regional Directors' Subcommittee to Committee on Administration (33pp); Madden's address before the National Conference on Civil Liberties; Dept. of Manufacture report on amendments; summary of unfair labor practices (21pp).
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        11/39-12/39; concerning the NLRB Union and the Smith Committee counter proposal; instructions regarding representatives (15pp); Leiserson's statement to the committee to investigate the NLRB; excerpt from Fulton Lewis Jr.'s speech.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
        1/40-3/40; relating to amendments to the NLRA Federal Register; the investigation of the Los Angeles office (100pp+); division of economic research case statistics; Madden's address on labor relations; John L. Lewis' statement on amendments to the NLRA (50pp+); an open letter from James P. Miller; Wagner's address on the Smith Amendments.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        4/40-12/40; pertaining to the NLRB Union's aggreement on grievance procedure; "A Square Deal for the Court" (18pp); report of NLRB to the Senate Committee on Education and Labor upon H.R.9195 (51pp); Madden and Edwin S. Smith addresses.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 12)
        1/41-5/41; regarding Congressional Record excerpts; H.R.3489 (36pp); field coordinators; compliance unit report; list of 40 questions; the Shipowners' Association of the Pacific Coast et al; administrative survey; addresses of Edwin S. Smith.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 13)
        6/41-12/41; concerning authorization committee procedure; address of Edwin S. Smith; executive order establishing the NWLB and the War Labor Disputes Coordinating Committee.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 14)
        relating to the compliance unit; Leiserson's speech "Labor Relations and the War"; H.R.6230 questionnaire.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 15)
        Report on the NWLB conference of 11/27/43.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 16)
        pertaining to statement of principles; "Restatement" of law on the question of plant versus craft units; excerpt of letter to Millis.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 17)
        relating to developments in NLRB decisional policy; John M. Huston's statement before the House Military Affairs Committee.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 18)
        concerning the addresses of James J. Reynolds, Jr. and Paul L. Styles; proposals for a legislative program in a strike situation; excerpt from the Daily Labor News; memo for the President's State of the Union Address.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 19)
        relating to the Administrative Procedures Act (39PP); proposed bill for the Labor- Management Relations Act (15pp); H.R. 725; impact of NLRB rulings on Foremen; restriction on Board's discretion with respect to craft units; the right of the NLRB to enter into a written agreement with the NLRB Union (26pp).
      - Interview with Wyzanski (35pp)., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Excerpt from Saposs interview, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Memorials for Judge J. Warren Madden., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 5, Folder 24)
        Undated; includes a list of regional directors; excerpt from Bott interview; positions of NLRB members regarding appropriate units (50pp); the NLRB on Freedom of the Press; proposed procedural changes in the Bill (58pp).
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 5, Folder 25)
        Undated; relating to personnel; separation of prosecuting and judicial functions; interstate commerce; restriction of right of the Board to set aside or modify its own order; contention that the NLRB is constituted both judge and prosecutor; reports by region; Crucible Steel.
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 5, Folder 26)
        Undated; pertaining to current events; instructions to trial examiners; suggested amendments; personnel; majority rule.
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 5, Folder 27)
        Undated; concerning litigation; Rules and Regulations; James P. Miller's suggested amendments (26pp); S.1000 (34pp); government worker's unions; Guffy decision; rules of evidence (31pp); appropriations; Seattle Regional Labor Board; Unions of NLRB Lawyers and Trial Examiners; James B. Carey's criticism of Board policy.
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 6, Folder 1)
        Undated; relating to cooperation with the Senate Committee; NLRB reply to Attorney General's Committee on Administrative Procedure (94pp); trial examiners (13pp); Senate vote on S.1126; addresses and speeches on the NLRA; reports from regional offices; H.R.4367; H.R.6172; guarantees of collective bargaining in government contract; Inland Steel Co.; "chronological index" (11pp).
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 6, Folder 2)
        Undated; regarding the NLRB Union; comparision in litigation, AFL-CIO, unaffilated unions (15pp); bills to amend the NLRA including H.R.5923 (permits discrimination or discharge of non-union employees); H.R.1575; analysis of H.R.880 (Hoffman); excerpt from Blakenhorn files concerning the senate investigation.
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Undated; pertaining to the legislative history of the Act (14pp); resume of issues presented by regional directors; procedure in showing interstate commerce; judicial interference with proceedings of the NLRB or its regional agencies (41pp); injunction procedure; S.1710 (Bland-Guffey Bill); conference with the WLRB; confidential regional officers' comments on the current labor situation; J. Warren Madden memorial by Shea; summary of plan of investigation adopted by senate sub-committee 8/4.
    - Sub-Series 4. CLIPPINGS AND REPRINTS 1934-77
      - Clippings, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Clippings, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Clippings, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        1/37-3/37
      - Clippings, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        4/37-7/37
      - Clippings, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 8)
        8/37-12/37
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
        1/38-4/38
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 10)
        5/38-6/38
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 11)
        Jul-38
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        8/1/38-8/20/38
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 13)
        8/21/38-8/31/38
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 14)
        9/38-10/38
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 15)
        11/38-12/38
      - Clippings, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
        1/39-6/39
      - Clippings, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 17)
        7/39-11/39
      - Clippings, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
        Dec-39
      - Clippings, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 19)
        Jan-40
      - Clippings, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 20)
        Feb-40
      - Clippings, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 21)
        Apr-40
      - Clippings, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 22)
        4/40-5/40
      - Clippings, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
        6/40-12/40
      - Clippings, 1941-1972 (Box 6, Folder 24)
        41-42, 44-48, 50-51, 72
      - Clippings (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Reprints, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Reprints, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Reprints, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Reprints, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 29)
        1/37-7/37
      - Reprints, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        8/37-11/37
      - Reprints, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        Dec-37
      - Reprints, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        1/38-2/38
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        3/38-4/38
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 7)
        7/38-8/38
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        Sep-38
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 9)
        10/38-12/38
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Reprints, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 12)
        1/39-3/39
      - Reprints, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 13)
        4/39-6/39
      - Reprints, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 14)
        7/39-9/39
      - Reprints, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 15)
        9/39-10/39
      - Reprints, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 16)
        11/39-12/39
      - Reprints, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Reprints, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Reprints, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 19)
        1/40-2/40
      - Reprints, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 20)
        Mar-40
      - Reprints, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        4/40-6/40
      - Reprints, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
        7/40-12/40
      - Reprints, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Reprints, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Reprints, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 5)
        1/41-11/41
      - Reprints, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Reprints, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Reprints, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Reprints, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Reprints, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Reprints, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 11)
        1/46-6/46
      - Reprints, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 12)
        7/46-12/46
      - Reprints, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Reprints, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Reprints, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Reprints, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Reprints, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Reprints, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Reprints, 1958-1977 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Reprints (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Reprints (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Reprints (Box 8, Folder 22)
        "The Trojan Horse in America," undated
    - Sub-Series 5. CASE FILES 1935-1945
      - A-F (Box 9, Folder 1)
        American Machine and Foundry Co.; American News Co., Inc.; American Oil Co.Inc.; American Potash and Chemical Co.; American Radiator Co.; Ansley Radio Corp.; Armour and Co.; Associated Press; Commonwealth Div. of General Steel Castings Corp.; Consolidated Aircraft Corp.; Beloit Iron Works; Bemis Bros. Bag Co.; Berkshire Knitting Mills; Biles Coleman Lumber Co.; Botany Worsted Mills; Brooklyn Daily Eagle; Brown Co.; Brown Shipbuilding Co.; California Walnut Growers Assn.;J.I. Case Co.; Cating Rope Works, Inc.; Colorado Fuel and Iron Co.; Columbian Enameling and Stamping Co.; Consolidated Edison Co. of New York; Corn Products Refining Co.; Crossett Lumber Co.; Joseph Dyson and Sons; Eagle Picher Mining and Smelting Co.; Ford; Friedman-Harry Marks Clothing Co.
      - G-L (Box 9, Folder 2)
        General Motors; Great Lakes Engineering Corp.; Grower-Shipper Vegetable Assn. of California; Guide Lamp Corp.; Harnischfeger Corp.; Heller series; Interlake Iron Corp.; International Merchantile Marine Co.; International Nickel Co. Inc.; Jones and Laughlin Steel Corp.; Constitutional cases; Kimberly-Clark Corp.; S.H. Kress and Co.; Christian A. Lund.
      - M-R (Box 9, Folder 3)
        Johns Manville Corp.; Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Studios; Moore Drudock Co.; Moorsville Cotton; National Cash Register Co.; National Casket Co. Inc.; National Sugar Refining Co.; Northrop Corp.; Oregon Worsted Co.; Pacific Greyhound Lines; Paper, Calmenson and Co.; Peyton Packing Co.; Remington Arms Co.; Republic Steel Corp.
      - S-Z (Box 9, Folder 4)
        Seas Shipping Co.; Servel, Inc.; Shell Oil Co.; Shipowners Assn. of the Pacific Coast; Southern Steamship Co.; Standard Lime and Stone Co.; Steel City Optical Corp.; Triplett Electrical Instrument Co.; Waggoner Refining Co. Inc.; Webster Manufacturing, Inc.; Williams Manufacturing Co.; Wilson and Co.
      - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 5)
        Related case file documents
  - Sub-Series B. DIVISION OF ECONOMIC RESEARCH RECORDS 1936-1973
    - Sub-Series 1. CORRESPONDENCE
      - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        Correspondence reporting on the Associated Press case; evidence in steel cases; materials in the National Recovery Administration files, Dept. of Commerce.
      - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        Correspondence relating to labor relations under the current political and economic situation; suggested plan of activities; to Harvey Hoshour (General Solicitor General, American Telephone and Telegraph Co.); evidence in hearings; reconsideration of economic data required in cases before Board (10pp); suggested subjects for general research; interstate commerce; Fahy regarding Wheeler's memoranda; circuit court briefs; personnel; jurisdictional proof; Liggett Drug Co..
      - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        Correspondence concerning written trade agreements; personnel; Iowa State College forestry graduates; Portland hotels; Idaho Maryland Mines Corp.; Baltimore Sun and Saposs; "Summary of Material Files of the Division of Economic Research" (17pp).
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 9)
        Correspondence pertaining to reclassification; quasi-judicial agencies (8pp); regional conference; personnel; collective bargaining in the rubber industry; Senator James J. Davis on the NLRA, the RLA and the Norris-LaGuardia Act; personnel policies in 8(3) cases; emergency problems (16pp+); House investigation of the Board.
      - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        Correspondence reporting on the Smith Committee Investigation; dairy cases; speech on company and independent unions; regional offices use of Division records; field services; employees engaged in marketing farm products; 8(3) cases and back pay; Senator McKellar tries to red bait Saposs; J. H. Heins Co.; personnel; Division name change; letters written about the Division; substantial correspondence relating to budget appropriations which eliminate the Division; Saposs to Millis concerning an appointment to the Mediation Board.
      - Correspondence, 1954-1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
        Correspondence relating to the Industrial Analysis Section; proposal for the establishment of a division of research; correspondence between James Gross and George Wheeler.
    - Sub-Series 2. Reports and Official Documents
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 12)
        concerning the use of economic data to support the constitutional basis of the Wagner Labor Relations Act (14pp); civil service exam for industrial economist.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 13)
        relating to the conference of field and departmental staff (50pp+).
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 14)
        concerning organization of the Division; suggested plan of activities; Commonwealth Steel Co.; Saposs' testimony in the Griswold Mfg. Co. case; essential elements for successful collective bargaining.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 15)
        pertaining to employer labor policies and activities (11pp); exhibits concerning: the Douglas Aircraft Co. Inc. sit-down strikes, the Liberty League, a decline in the importance of sit down strikes and other related issues; "Summary of Files of the Division of Economic Research" (44pp).
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 16)
        regarding determination of appropriate bargaining unit (9pp); renewed efforts to promote company unions under the guise of "independents" (39pp); functional analysis of the Division's work; interstate commerce (24pp); transcript of hearings.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 17)
        concerning proposed amendment on determination of appropriate bargaining unit; refutation of U.S. Chamber of Commerce Statement (8pp); cases involving largest companies and subsidiaries; employees engaged in marketing farm products; functions of the Division (15pp); use of non-legal expert personnel; retention of the Division.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 18)
        regarding the proposal for a division of research and statistics; placement of Industrial Analysis Branch (IAB) in the agency (10pp); organization of welders; midwest piping doctrine (20pp).
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 9, Folder 19)
        Undated; concerning preliminary survey of the cotton textile industry (9pp); H.R. 9007 elimination of the Division (9pp); legality of the appointment of Daivd Saposs as Chief Economist of the Board.
- Series IV. RELATED COMMITTEES
  - Sub-Series A. LAFOLLETTE (Robert) COMMITTEE 1935-1940
    - Sub-Series 1. CORRESPONDENCE
      - Correspondence, 1935-1937 (Box 9, Folder 20)
        Correspondence relating to hearings on the LaFollette Resolution; the LaFollette Subcommittee for the Investigation of Violations of Free Speech and Assembly and the Rights of Labor to Organize and Bargain Collectively; the Senate Sub-Committee of the Committee on Education and Labor, Under S.R. 266; Blakenhorn memos on the LaFollette Investigation; the Citizen's Alliance; B.A. Green's (Green, Tanner and Boesen Lawyers) discussion of the political situation in Oregon; substantial correspondence from Robert Wohlforth (Secretary, Sub-Committee of the Committee on Education and Labor Under S.R.266) and E.J. Eagen (Investigator, Sub-Committee of the Committee on Education and Labor) concerning the West Coast situation; the Carnegie-Illinois hearings; Continental Can and Pinkerton; Federal Laboratories; administrative correspondence relating to the organization of committees; finances; cooperation with Senate Civil Liberties Committees and other committees.
      - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 21)
        Correspondence concerning special procedure to deal with detective agencies; the California brewers situation and racketeer John Lombardi (John Lombardi Rossie); the La Follette Act 1939; LaFollette Committee legislation; NLRB views of the LaFollette Bill; Roosevelt's sentiments on the Senate Civil Liberties Committee; LaFollette attendance on NLRA amendments; status of the LaFollette-Thomas- Wood Bill; M-1033 (concerns Labor Board members who worked with the LaFollette Committee); important cases, such as the Post Intelligencer (P.I.), and the Alaska Juneau cases; Toland's request for LaFollette Committee files.
      - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 22)
        Undated; Correspondence relating to Cranefield; cooperation with the LaFollette Committee; LaFollette Civil Liberties Committee Records.
    - Sub-Series 2. REPORTS AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1935-1939 (Box 9, Folder 23)
        concerning cooperation of the NLRB with the Civil Liberties Sub-Committee of the Committee on Education and Labor, U.S.Senate, 1936-39 (14pp); Board's first decision on an espionage case; notes on the Pinkerton System; informal reports; tabulations sumarizing details of NLRB's employees to Senate Civil Liberties Committee (8pp); report of interview with Lester Levin.
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 9, Folder 24)
        Undated; relating to LaFollette Committee materials in the J.G. Boswell Co. case to be used in the Smith Committee hearings; cooperation with the Senate Civil Liberties Sub-Committee; partial testimony in the California brewers situation (8pp); profiles of: C.A."Tanner" Smith (7pp); Slivershirts; Industrial Council of Washington, Inc.; Associated Industries of Seattle (11pp); Law and Order League; industrial lawyers object to uncovering espionage.
  - Sub-Series B. DIES (Martin) COMMITTEE RECORDS 1938-1940
    - Sub-Series 1. CORRESPONDENCE
      - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 25)
        Correspondence pertaining to the Sub-Committee of the Special Committee to Investigate Un-American Activities record of 11/7/38 hearing (9pp); clipping from Donald Wakefield Smith; Joseph Curran to the President discussing the negative effects the Dies Committee is having on his union and trade unions in general.